JASON SWEENEY

Web Developer

Brisbane, AU / Edinburgh, UK

+61 406 997 441

github.com/jsonsweeney

in /in/jsonsweeney

isonsweeney.com

SUMMARY

Creative and passionate web developer with a first-class honours degree in Computer Science. Successfully developed and launched a SaaS product which earned an Innovation Award. Transitioned from two years of part-time web development experience to an instructor role at a digital skills academy, furthering my communication, technical, and leadership skills. After an adventurous year travelling and working in Australia, I'm eager to return to the world of tech.

SKILLS -

Languages:

Python, JavaScript, TypeScript, Java, PHP, SQL

Frameworks/Technologies:

React, Django, Redis, PostgreSQL, Spring Boot, React Native, MongoDB, Next.js, D3.js, Docker, Figma

Core Skills:

Creativity, Problem-Solving, Leadership, Adaptability, Strong Communication

EDUCATION -

2019 - 2023

BSc Computer Science (First-Class Honours)

Heriot-Watt University, Edinburgh

• Coursework: Data Structures & Algorithms, Data Mining & Machine Learning, Statistical Modelling & Analysis, Data Visualisation, Spoken Language Processing, Software Engineering

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

9/2022 - 11/2023 **Software Instructor**

CodeClan, Scotland

- Led a 16-week intensive cohort of 20+ students in **Python (Flask)**, **JavaScript (Express/React/MongoDB)**, and **Java (Spring Boot)** courses, adapting content to suit my teaching style.
- · Delivered a 10-week Web Development course on building a **Django** web app.
- · Instructed various short courses covering data analysis, web development, and Python for beginners.
- · Collaborated with team members to successfully achieve course objectives.

9/2020 - 9/2022 Web Developer (Part-time)

Web Integrations LTD, Scotland

- Contributed to the development and maintenance of websites using PHP-based frameworks (Word-Press, SilverStripe, CraftCMS) for both new projects and existing clients' sites.
- Maintained consistent communication with the rest of the team through Slack to ensure project deadlines were being met.
- · Worked with designers to outline requirements needed for the development of website projects.
- Communicated with clients to discuss improvements and assist with changes to their websites.

OTHER EXPERIENCE

5/2023 - Present Bartender

Verona Fresh Italian, Birtinya

· Applied my mixology knowledge to craft new cocktails for our menu.

12/2023 - 4/2024 Junior Sommelier

Olivine Wine Bar, Melbourne

 $\cdot \ \ \text{Learned wine pouring techniques and vocabulary to provide a high level of service at a hatted venue.}$

PROJECTS -

2022 - 2023 **Coreer**

GitHub

A mobile app to allow users to match with professionals based on programming languages and interests.

- Filtered and cleaned a dataset of 10M GitHub users to produce a subset of data (168k) that could be used to build and test a hybrid recommender system
- Implemented a redis database to store similarity matrices which improved recommendation time by 66%, and to manage real-time communication for the messaging interface
- Designed a high-fidelity prototype in Figma, and built a mobile and web interface using Next.js/TypeScript/React Native, and the REST API using Django Rest Framework

2021 - 2022

readysetrota

GitHub

A shift management application that I built for the hospitality industry to be affordable and intuitive.

- Submitted a business plan and delivered a 3-minute pitch for an Innovation Challenge held by my university, successfully winning the Innovation Award and receiving £8k of funding
- Built the frontend using React/Redux to develop a complex user interface for viewing and publishing shifts, and a REST API using Django Rest Framework
- · Implemented a per-seat pricing model using Stripe